So far, we've investigated how to train
我们已经学习了
an MLP to classify handwritten digits in the MNIST dataset,
如何训练 MLP 对 MNIST 数据集中的手写数字进行分类
and we got a really high test accuracy.
并且获得了很高的测试准确率
MLPs are a nice solution in this case.
MLP 很适合解决此类问题
Some other solutions for the MNIST classification task and
下面的链接部分提供了 MNIST 分类任务的其他解决方案
their errors on the test dataset can be explored at the link provided below.
以及它们在测试数据集上的错误率
You'll find that the best algorithms or the ones with
你会发现最佳算法或测试错误率最低的方案
the least test error are the approaches that use convolutional neural networks or CNNs.
使用的是卷积神经网络 (CNN)
In fact, for most image classification tasks,
实际上 对于大多数图像分类任务来说
CNNs and MLPs do not even compare,
CNN 和 MLP 不能相提并论
CNNs do much better.
CNN 效果好多了
The MNIST database is an exception,
MNIST 数据库是一个特例
and that it's very clean and pre-processed.
因为它非常整洁并且经过预处理
All images of digits are roughly the same size and are centered in a 28 by 28 pixel grid.
所有数字图像大小大致相等 并且在 28x28 像素网格中居中
You can imagine that if instead of having to
假设要分类的数字图像
classify the digit within these very clean images,
不是这么整洁
you had to work with images where the digit could appear anywhere within the grid,
数字可能会出现中网格中的任何位置
and sometimes appear quite small or quite large.
有时候很小 有时候很大
It would be a more challenging task for an MLP.
这对 MLP 来说将更有挑战
In the case of real-world messy image data,
在现实中 图像数据很混乱
CNNs will truly shine over MLPs.
对于这类图像 CNN 的效果比 MLP 强很多
For some intuition for why this might be the case,
解释下原因
we saw that in order to feed an image to an MLP,
为了将图像传入 MLP 中
you must first convert the image to a vector.
必须首先将图像转换为向量
The MLP then treats this converted image as
MLP 然后将转换后的图像
a simple vector of numbers with no special structure.
当做简单的数字向量 没有特殊结构
It has no knowledge of the fact that
它不知道这些数字
these numbers were originally spatially arranged in a grid.
原先是位于网格空间里的数字
CNNs, in contrast, are built for the exact purpose
相反 CNN 可以专门处理这种情形
of working with or elucidating the patterns in multidimensional data.
CNN 能够分析多维数据中的规律
Unlike MLPs, CNNs understand the fact that image pixels that are closer
与 MLP 不同，CNN 可以判断出相互靠近的图像像素
in proximity to each other are more heavily related than pixels that are far apart.
比相互离得更远的像素关系更紧密
In this section, Alexis and I will discuss the math behind this kind of understanding.
在此部分 我和 Alexis 将讨论 CNN 的数学原理
We'll present different types of layers that make up a CNN,
我们将介绍构成 CNN 的不同层级
and provide some intuition about each of their roles in
并讲解它们在处理输入
processing an input and forming a complete neural network.
以及形成完整神经网络中的角色